const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "in HTML, a tag used as an alternative to make text bold is",
    options: {
      a: "<bold>",
      b: "<double>",
      c: "<strong>",
      d: "<dark>",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "<strong>",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "In HTML forms, form elements are different type of",
    options: {
      a: "Input elements",
      b: "Text fields",
      c: "Submit buttons",
      d: "All of the Above",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "All of the Above",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "A tag known to be fundamental HTML block is",
    options: {
      a: "<!DOCTYPE>",
      b: "<HTML>",
      c: "<BODY>",
      d: "<P>",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "<HTML>",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "Defining a special style for special table, the added attribute should be of",
    options: {
      a: "<class>",
      b: "<padding>",
      c: "<id>",
      d: "<tr>",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "<id>",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "In HTML, the element <html> defines the",
    options: {
      a: "Element",
      b: "Function",
      c: "Whole document",
      d: "Content",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "Whole document",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "The number of attributes required for <div> element, is/are of",
    options: {
      a: '0',
      b: '1',
      c: '2',
      d: '3',
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: '0',
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "A client side script is defined by the tag",
    options: {
      a: "<clientscript>",
      b: "<script>",
      c: "<jcscript>",
      d: "<javascript>",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "<script>",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "The default display value for most of the HTML elements are",
    options: {
      a: "Block",
      b: "Inline",
      c: "External",
      d: "A and B",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "A and B",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "Element used as a container for other HTML elements known as",
    options: {
      a: "<id>",
      b: "<div>",
      c: "<class>",
      d: "<span>",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "<div>",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "The HTML element known to be <del>, defines",
    options: {
      a: "Deleted data",
      b: "Removed data",
      c: "Crossed data",
      d: "Overwritten data",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "Removed data",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "In Javascript, the data type of an array is",
    options: {
      a: "Char",
      b: "int",
      c: "object",
      d: "NaN",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "object",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question:
      "In HTML, a specific style for a special element can be defined by the attribute",
    options: {
      a: "<style>",
      b: "<header>",
      c: "<id>",
      d: "<special>",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "<id>",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "In Javascript, the data type of NaN is",
    options: {
      a: "Null",
      b: "Undefined",
      c: "Character",
      d: "Number",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "Number",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "In HTML, the unvisited links are specified in color",
    options: {
      a: "Purple",
      b: "Red",
      c: "Blue",
      d: "Green",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "Blue",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: "An array method named splice() is used for",
    options: {
      a: "Insertion",
      b: "Deletion",
      c: "Updation",
      d: "Length retrieving",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "Insertion",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: "Inside which HTML element do we put the JavaScript?",
    options: {
      a: "<scripting>",
      b: "<javascript>",
      c: "<script>",
      d: "<js>",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "<script>",
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: "Among the following, which one is a ternary operator?",
    options: {
      a: "+",
      b: ":",
      c: "-",
      d: "?:",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "?:",
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: "Which of the following is not a valid javascript variable name?",
    options: {
      a: "2names",
      b: "_first_and_last",
      c: "FirstAndLast",
      d: "None of the above",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "2names",
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question:
      "Which of the following is not considered as javascript operator?",
    options: {
      a: "new",
      b: "this",
      c: "delete",
      d: "typeof",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "this",
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question:
      "Which method evaluates a string of Javascript code in the context of the specified object?",
    options: {
      a: "Eval",
      b: "ParseInt",
      c: "ParseFloat",
      d: "Efloat",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "Eval",
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question:
      "Which of the following event fires when the form element loses the focus on its child elements",
    options: {
      a: "onfocus",
      b: "onblur",
      c: "onclick",
      d: "ondbclick",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "onblur",
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: "Which statement is used to test for a specific condition",
    options: {
      a: "Select",
      b: "If",
      c: "Switch",
      d: "For",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "If",
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question:
      "The ______ method of an array object adds and/or removes elements from an array",
    options: {
      a: "Reverse",
      b: "Shift",
      c: "Slice",
      d: "Splice",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "Splice",
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: "Choose the client-side javascript object:",
    options: {
      a: "Database",
      b: "Cursor",
      c: "Client",
      d: "FileUpload",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "FileUpload",
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: "What will be the output of 2+5+'8'",
    options: {
      a: '258',
      b: "Error",
      c: '7',
      d: '78',
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: '78',
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: "Which of the following is not a reserved word in JavaScript?",
    options: {
      a: "interface",
      b: "throws",
      c: "program",
      d: "short",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "program",
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: "The 'function' and 'var' are known as:",
    options: {
      a: "Keywords",
      b: "Data types",
      c: "Declaration statements",
      d: "Prototypes",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "Declaration statements",
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question:
      "Which of the following variables takes precedence over the others if the names are the same?",
    options: {
      a: "Global variable",
      b: "The local element",
      c: "The two of the above",
      d: "None of the above",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "The local element",
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question:
      "In the JavaScript, which one of the following is not considered as an error:",
    options: {
      a: "Syntax error",
      b: "Missing of semicolons",
      c: "Division by zero",
      d: "Missing of Bracket",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "Division by zero",
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question:
      "Choose the correct snippet from the following to check if the variable 'a' is not equal the 'NULL':",
    options: {
      a: "if(a!==null)",
      b: "if (a!)",
      c: "if(a!null)",
      d: "if(a!=null)",
    },
    selectedAnswer: null,
    answer: "if(a!==null)",
  },
];
export default questions;
